<resources>
    <string name="app_name">UVMe</string>

    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="ble_not_supported">BLE is not supported</string>
    <string name="label_data">Data:</string>


    <string name="label_device_address">Device address:</string>
    <string name="label_state">State:</string>
    <string name="no_data">No data</string>
    <string name="connected">Connected</string>
    <string name="disconnected">Disconnected</string>
    <string name="title_devices">UV Sensor BLE Device Scan</string>
    <string name="error_bluetooth_not_supported">Bluetooth not supported.</string>
    <string name="unknown_device">Unknown device</string>
    <string name="unknown_characteristic">Unknown characteristic</string>

    <string name="unknown_service">Unknown service</string>
    <string name="menu_connect">Connect</string>
    <string name="menu_disconnect">Disconnect</string>

    <!-- Menu items -->
    <string name="menu_scan">Scan</string>
    <string name="menu_stop">Stop</string>
    <string name="ok_terms_of_service">You chose OK action for Terms of Services</string>
    <string name="cancel_terms_of_service">You chose Cancel action for Terms of Services</string>


    <!-- Disclaimer Dialog -->
    <string name="terms_of_services">Terms of Services</string>
    <string name="warning_label">
        WARNING: PLEASE READ THE DISCLAIMER BEFORE USING THIS APPLICATION\n
        \nThe UVMe app device and sensor are tools to help you enjoy your time in the sun.
        The purpose of the sensor and the app is to help reduce Ultraviolet (UV) exposure
        and avoid skin damage such as sunburns and skin damage. It is for personal use and
        may not be used as for medicinal advice. The information provided is not intended
        for treatment, diagnoses, nor for prevent or curing any diseases. Persons using
        the data within for medical purposes such as avoiding sun exposure for medical
        purposes, should not rely solely on the accuracy of the data herein. Some
        medicines and over the-counter drugs can cause the skin to sunburn very
        quickly. Talk with a medical specialist or pharmacist.
        \n
        \nThe calculations and formulas in the application are based on information
        provided by a variety of sources and cannot be exact. We do not have control
        on the accuracy of the input data by the users or their use of the device.
        The UVMe device can accurately measure UV ratings when properly used and
        functioning.
        \n
        \nThe application without connection to the UVMe device cannot measure to the
        actual amount of UV. The application calculates the amount of UV radiation
        based on UV index data available from https://www.epa.gov. All UV index
        forecasts have inaccuracies because they are predictions. https://www.epa.gov
        cannot be held responsible for any consequences that may result from the use
        of this application.\n
        \nThank you for using UVMe.
    </string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="title_activity_help">HelpActivity</string>
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>
    <string name="hello_first_fragment">Hello first fragment</string>
    <string name="hello_second_fragment">Hello second fragment. Arg: %1$s</string>

    <string-array name="gender">
        <item>Male</item>
        <item>Female</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="Time">
        <item>Day</item>
        <item>Week</item>
        <item>Month</item>
        <item>Year</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>

